# Jerid Hedrick

## **Temporary Lead Avionics Troubleshooter**

Philadelphia, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Jerid-Hedrick/8482497ba495a407

Successfully gain employment as an Engineer within your company, and further my knowledge in the field of electronics. My leadership, experience and professional studies in Electrical Systems, Schematic Analysis, and in depth troubleshooting of complex electrical systems can be used effectively to benefit your company.

#### PROFESSIONAL OCCUPATION DESCRIPTION:

• Installing, troubleshooting, repairing, testing, maintaining and calibrating medical equipment and systems, components, and sub-assemblies. Completing performance verifications, preventive maintenance, functional audits, and acceptance testing of medical equipment/systems; applying computer and network knowledge to Biomedical Engineering functions on medical devices and medical device systems and measurement instrumentation; requisitioning parts from vendor sources; determining the priority of work; performing biomedical equipment control, operator training, and providing technical assistance pertaining to medical equipment technology; communicating with customers, vendors, and staff to solicit information and document maintenance; interpreting and applying technical data such as schematic drawings, wiring diagrams. Authorized to work in the US for any employer

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

### **Temporary Lead Avionics Troubleshooter**

Sikorsky Global Helicopters - Coatesville, PA - September 2012 to February 2014

Reads and interprets wiring schematics. Demonstrates strong verbal and written communication through shift turn overs, task assignments, and pass downs. Coordinates with Supervisors, aircraft managers and Engineering Department on changes to schematics and diagrams. Superior understanding of technical drawings, ensures correct running and marking of wires to install complex wiring and electrical systems. Performs continuity checkouts after work has been completed to verify proper terminations/installation. Troubleshoots avionics system on board aircraft, and assists all shops to ensure aircraft are completed on or before schedule.

Demonstrates strong knowledge of Solumina, Sikorsky 360, and Nirvana to ensure workload priorities are met. Understand practices of BAER and ITAR items. Strong working knowledge and implementation of ACE standards, practices, and tools. Demonstrates understanding of all cardinal rules, hazmat utilization procedures, and safety practices.

Received the Sikorsky Above and Beyond Award for dedicated excellence and going above the call of duty to ensure all goals were met and surpassed.

Udairi - KW - July 2012 to September 2012

Performed maintenance on the UH/HH-60

Perform Routine, Daily, Special and Phase inspections on UH/HH-60. Duties to include: installation/ removal on all aircraft subsystems, engines, rotors, gearboxes, and transmission system. Service and lubricate all Applicable components. Prepare aircraft documentation on ULLS-A and use STAMIS system. Routinely perform maintenance on aircraft electrical systems.

#### Assist in desert modifications

Phase Shop - Norfolk, VA - January 2006 to June 2011

Scheduled 175 Flight Hour In-Depth Inspection) Depot Level

Phase inspections to include: multi-system troubleshooting, back shop avionics termination of wires/ electrical systems, aircraft wire termination/repair, complete break down and repair of major components, use electrical schematics efficiently, electrical wire checks, read outs, and installations. Specialize in Wire Connector Repair, schematic layouts and reading, wire readouts and checks, modification to wiring systems, modifications to aircraft frame and corrosion prevention. Perform necessary documentation using Vids/Maf, IETMS and OOMA.

Avionics Shop (Unscheduled/scheduled Maintenance)

Avionics shop duties include: proper handling, installation and removal of electrical components. Demonstrate proficient us with all hand held tools, multimeter, time and frequency domain reflectometer, and associated aircraft test equipment. Responsible for supervising and completing all aircraft repairs in a correct, safe and time efficient manner. Completed read outs, terminations, modifications to essential aircraft systems and subsystems.

Assist in desert modifications for both MH-60 and UH-60 electrical systems. Assisted L3 Contractors on UH-60 "Black hawk" Aircraft Avionics troubleshooting

While deployed to Camp Buehring, Kuwait.

#### **EDUCATION**

Aviation Electronics Technician - Norfolk, VA 2006

"C" School - Norfolk, VA 2006

#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Work Center 210 (Avionics) Collateral Duty Quality Assurance Rep.
- Work Center 220 (Electrical) Collateral Duty Quality Assurance Rep.
- Work Center 310 (Flight Line) Collateral Duty Quality Assurance Rep.
- Work Center 12C(Corrosion) Collateral Duty Quality Assurance Rep Basic Corrosion Control (US Navy Class)
- Avionics Corrosion Control (US Navy Class)
- MH-60S Plane Captain (Perform all daily, pre/ post flight, turnaround, corrosion, and security inspections on the aircraft)